It will take you a million light years from home. But will it bring you back?
Stargate is a action, adventure, science fiction
film directed by Roland Emmerich.
An interstellar teleportation device, found in Egypt, leads to a planet with
humans resembling ancient Egyptians who worship the god Ra.
Dr. Daniel Jackson, played by James Spader.
Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil, played by Kurt Russell.
Ra, played by Jaye Davidson.
Catherine, played by Viveca Lindfors.
Skaara, played by Alexis Cruz.
Sha'uri, played by Mili Avital.
Stargate is a 1994 science fiction action-adventure film directed by
Roland Emmerich, written by Emmerich and Dean Devlin.
The film is the first entry in the eponymous media franchise and stars Kurt Russell,
James Spader, Jaye Davidson, Alexis Cruz, Mili Avital, and Viveca Lindfors.
The plot centers on the "Stargate", an ancient ring-shaped device that creates a
wormhole, enabling travel to a similar device elsewhere in the universe.
The central plot explores the theory of extraterrestrial beings
having an influence upon human civilization.
Stargate was released on October 28, 1994, by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer in the
United States, while it was released by AMLF in France.
The film received mixed reviews, with its atmosphere, story,
characters, and graphic content both praised and criticized.
The film grossed $196.6 million worldwide against a
production budget of $55 million.
The film explores themes of egypt, teleportation,
pyramid, space travel, uprising.
The tone is thought_provoking.